Vincent Mugambi

+254703784709 vinmugambi17@gmail.com Linkedin Nairobi, Kenya

SUMMARY

I am a talented software engineer interested in the development of mobile & web applications, distributed systems and cognitive services. I have four years of experience building web mobile applications, collaborating in cross functional teams and creating value using technology.

SKILLS

- Programming using TypeScript (Node.js, React, Vue), PHP (Laravel), and Kotlin (Compose)
- Data modeling (MySQL and Mongo), analysis, backup, and security
- Developing, documenting and consuming RESTful APIs
- Designing, building and integrating event driven services
- System planning, architecture, design(OOP), and analysis
- CI/CD with tools like Github workflows and Docker
- System testing, debugging, tracking and monitoring
- Collaboration using Git and business tools like Slack and Jira

EXPERIENCE

Participate Learning Nairobi, Kenya Full-Stack Engineer Nov 2022 to Now

Built pamoja.club, a cross platform app to plan, manage and fund-raise for community events.

- Outline, prioritize, schedule and scope software specifications
- Plan, design and develop the pamoja.club mobile application from scratch
- Integrated Mpesa, Zoho using fault tolerant, secure and scalable microservices

Tools: TypeScript, Neo4J, Postgres, React, Xstate, Remix, Graph QL, Tailwind CSSAzure Orchestrators I built the https://lipia.net mobile app, a simple way to buy airtime for all networks in Kenya

- Design an implement discount, cashbacks and referral services
- Integrate Mpesa and Equity bank's Jenga API

Tools: TypeScript, Remix, React, Redux, Ionic, Tailwind CSS, SQLite, Cloudfare workers

Adanian Labs
Nairobi, Kenya
Full-Stack Engineer
Aug 2021 to Aug 2022

moovebeta.com was a mobile app that allowed cross-border money transfers.

- Designed, built, documented and deployed the APIs that powered it.
- Integrated Flutterwave, Mpesa, Airtel Apis.
- Lead a team of three engineers to ship a Fintech application built from scratch

Tools: TypeScript, NestJs, Azure VM, Docker, Postgres, Swagger OpenAPI, Java Springboot Adalabs Adapay is a payment aggregator used by Startups in the Adanian Labs Accelerator.

• Monitored the application, fixed bugs on request.

Tools: Azure Monitor, PHP Laravel, MySQL, VueJs, Java, Tailwind CSS

Deveint Nairobi, Kenya Full-Stack Developer March 2021 to Jun 2021

• Built an app to manage subscriptions to the Botswana Stock Exchange.

Tools: PHP Laravel, Vuels, Vuetify, Vuex, Bootstrap,

Mountain Hike Safaris

Nairobi, Kenya

Web developer and IT helpdesk

March 2018 to Nov 2020

- Built an internal application to manage, track and print branded invoices.
- Made the company's first website.
- Maintained hardware and software
- Trained staff to use the Amadeus reservation software

Tools: Postgres, TypeScript. NuxtJs, Netlify, Vuex, JQuery, Bootstrap

Safaricom Nairobi, Kenya

Technology Intern

Nov 2017 to Feb 2018

• Part of a team that designed a deaf assistant glove that won the internal innovation challenge

Kenya National Bureau of Statistics

Nairobi, Kenya

Data Analyst Intern

May 2017 to Aug 2017

- Analyzed government education statistics data using SPSS.
- Consolidated budgets from all KNBS county offices.

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Azure Al Engineer Associate

June 2024

EDUCATION

Maseno university

Kisumu, Kenya

Bsc. in Mathematics and Computer Science (2nd class Honors – upper)

Sep 2013 to Dec 2017

In my final year I created an application to run online surveys using React, Node and Mongo

Murang'a High School

Muranga, Kenya

KCPE (A-)

Feb 2009 to Dec 2012

INTERESTS

I'm an avid reader and writer. I am always improving the way I think and act. I occasionally blog at <u>vinmugambi.github.io</u> and <u>mougambi.mataroa.blog</u>. I enjoy skating with friends and spending time with family.